## **Ben Little**

ben.little@benlittle.dev 814-954-0051 Boulder, CO 80304 https://benlittle.dev

#### Summary

Cloud-native software engineer and mathematician looking to work with an academically and culturally diverse group of scientists, engineers, and developers. I have **1.5 years of experience using containerized deployments** and write application code in a variety of languages. I strive to build applications that **fail early** and provide **quantifiable guarantees** about computational correctness and service level.

#### **Technical Overview**

Languages Python, Go, Javascript, Raku, others

Frameworks Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, OAuth2, gRPC

CI/CD GitLab CI, Google Cloud Build

Cloud Technology Terraform, Google Compute Engine, BigQuery, IAM

**Skills** 

Machine Learning Tensorflow, Scikit Learn, MiniMax/UCT/AlphaZero

Linear Algebra Lie theory, representation theory, exterior calculus

Optimization Variational methods, gradient descent, Hamiltonian Monte Carlo

Computer Science Logic, dependent type theory, complexity theory

Physics Quantum mechanics, relativity, and modern geometry

#### **Employment History**

Special Projects Engineer

Fruition, Denver, CO May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Manage day-to-day Kubernetes operations
- Maintain git repositories
- Deploy infrastructure on Google Cloud Platform
- Write CI/CD pipelines for building, testing, and deploying applications
- Write application code in a variety of languages using test-driven development
- Assist in development of dev ops practices and standards

Machine Learning Specialist Fruition, Denver, CO June 2018 - May 2020

 Study development team's practices related to data reporting and use

# **Ben Little**

ben.little@benlittle.dev	814-954-0051		Boulder, CO 80304	https://benlittle.dev
	Write applications for extracting and transforming data using cloud tools			
Research and Development Engineer	Penn State, State College, PA 2015 - 2017			
	intelli • Provi	intelligence		

### **Education**

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics Physics Minor The Pennsylvania State University 2015